Sean Hildebrandt Commercial Manager

Email seanhildebrandt@hotmail.com

Telephone 07515546521 **Date of Birth** 13/02/1984

Nationality British

Address Northop, Wales, UK

Professional Qualifications

University of Liverpool
Law
LLB (Hons)

University of Reading
Surveying

2007 - 2009
Post Grad Diploma

Chartered Institute of Arbitrators Ongoing

Member (MCIArb)

Summary of Experience

A highly motivated and delivery focussed commercial professional with 14 years international experience in the commercial management of projects across the Oil and Gas, Nuclear, Utilities and Construction industries.

Having joined a global FTSE 250 engineering and project management company on their advanced commercial graduate scheme, I quickly progressed to senior project and corporate positions. This demonstrates exceptional drive, commercial acumen, relationship management and an ability to successfully close challenging issues.

Professional Experience

Wood* (Nov 2005- Present)
*Previously AMEC and Amec Foster Wheeler

Wood Nuclear Business Service Line, Commercial Manager

Key Duties:

Responsible for Pre and Post Contract activities for a business service line (annual revenue of C. £45m)

Review and negotiation of main contract and subcontract terms and conditions Preparation and negotiation of disputes, renumeration models and variations

Review and approval of estimates and tender submissions

Building relationships with key internal and external customer focal points

Wood Transmission and Distribution Commercial Manager

Client: Wales & West Utilities

Scope: Upgrade of Gas Distribution Network

Contract: NEC 3 Option C: Target Cost with activity schedule (2005)

Contract Value: £60m per annum

Key Duties:

Newport, South Wales. April 2017- July 2018

Knutsford, UK.

July 2018- Present

Member of Alliance Leadership Team
Responsible for all post-contract commercial activities
Oversight of valuations, forecasting, cost value reconciliations, system data and reporting activities
Subcontractor Management: overseeing all aspects of pre-contract and post-contract activities
(subcontractor expenditure £10m+ per annum)
Drive change management / compensation events
Dispute resolution: review viability of claims and negotiation of them
Implement cost control and margin improvement plan with partners
Owned risk management process to ensure informed decisions are taken and key issues are actioned

AMEC International Limited, Country Commercial Manager

Abu Dhabi, UAE Aug 2013- April 2017

Key Duties:

Responsible for Pre and Post Contract activities for a portfolio of projects (annual revenue of C. £90m)

Pre Contract activities include:

- o Review and supervision of contractual negotiations, estimates and bonds / PCG's
- o Commercial representative on Commercial Review Board to approve tender submissions (Delegated Authority to approve submissions up to \$50m)
- o Working with business development to agree key prospects and pricing strategies

Post Contract activities include:

- o Review and approval of VOWD, Valuations and Client Cost Reports
- o Review and approval of project P&L reports including risk provisions
- o Preparation and negotiation of claims and variations (up to \$200m)
- o Subcontractor management ('cradle to grave')
- o Management of risk identification and mitigation

Deputise for UAE Country Operations Manager Leadership of 6 direct commercial resources

AMEC Natural Resources, MonArb Re-development Project Commercial Team Lead

Aberdeen, Scotland. Jan 2012- Aug 2013

Client: Talisman Sinopec

Scope: EPC

Contract: Logic Construction Edition 2, October 2003

Contract Value: £100m (Call Off #1)

Key Duties:

Commercial focal point of tender team that secured a 5 year Framework Agreement

Integral part of the management team during detailed negotiations to finalise the target cost estimate and remuneration model for the MonArb Call Off Order

Reported directly to the project manager, corporate management and client project manager

Management of invoicing, forecasting, cost value reconciliations, system data and reporting activities

Subcontractor Management: overseeing all aspects of pre-contract and post-contract activities (procurement budget of £9m+)

Review and preparation of contract documentation and amendments

Management of KPI mechanism to maximise return of variable profit

AMEC Natural Resources, Britannia Long Term Compression Project* Commercial Team Lead

Aberdeen, Scotland. Sept 2011- Dec 2011

Client: ConocoPhillips

Scope: EPC

Contract: Client Bespoke Contract Value: £45m

Key Duties:

Reported directly to the project manager, corporate management and client Subcontractor Management: overseeing all aspects of pre-contract and post-contract activities Review and preparation of contract documentation & amendments Management of invoicing, forecasting, cost value reconciliations, system data and reporting activities Liaised with the client to restructure KPI profit mechanism and settlement of existing KPI's Successful renegotiation of the remuneration section of the contract *Short duration due to planned internal overseas assignment. AMEC Natural Resources, Facilities Engineering Aberdeen, Scotland. Oct 2008- Sep 2011 Senior Quantity Surveyor Main Clients: Apache, Bluewater and Maersk Scope: EPC Contract Value: £25m per annum **Key Duties:** Reported directly to the project manager, corporate management and client Responsible for all commercial and cost activities of the projects Management and development of three direct reports Pre-contract negotiations, project set-up and building/ maintaining relationships Preparation, review and negotiation of call off and other contractual documentation Negotiation of contract remuneration sections Resolution of contractual/ commercial queries and disputes AMEC Natural Resources, Britannia Satellites Project Aberdeen, Scotland. **Commercial Graduate** Oct 2007 - Oct 2008 Client: ConocoPhillips Scope: EPC Contract: Client Bespoke Contract Value: £250m Key Duties: Client invoicing and cost forecasting Assisting client claims team in a successful claim against the fabricator Assisting with ad hoc commercial issues **AMEC Environmental & Infrastructure Corporate Contracts Department** Philadelphia, USA. Apr 2007 - Oct 2007 **Graduate Quantity Surveyor Key Duties:** Review of AMEC's standard contractual documentation Preparation and review of construction subcontracts Review of subcontractor proposals and subsequent negotiations Secondment part of graduate development programme AMEC Natural Resources,

AMEC Natural Resources, Corporate Contracts Department Graduate Quantity Surveyor

Aberdeen, Scotland. Aug 2006 - Apr 2007

Key Duties:

- Built on existing knowledge of contractual documentation and qualification of terms and conditions in line with companies contracting principles
- Assisted AMEC's subcontract team in Azerbaijan during a platform shutdown working with the project team in a high pressure environment to ensure the relevant commitments were in place

AMEC Design and Project Services, Leftbank Apartments Project Graduate Quantity Surveyor

Manchester, England. Nov 2005 – Aug 2006

Client: Westbury Homes

Scope: EPC

Contract: JCT Design and Build Contract Value: £56m (Lump Sum)

Key Duties:

1 of 2 graduates recruited for PLC Commercial Directors graduate development scheme
Acquired a working knowledge of the commercial aspects of a major construction project
Assisted the commercial manager resolve subcontractor disputes and agree final accounts
Managed numerous small subcontract packages

Interests

Running, golf, cycling, travelling and spending time with my family

References

Available on request